Yves Accad

3845 Altura Ave, CA 91214 | C: 8184348357 | yves@accadius.com

Summary

Accomplished Senior Network and Systems Security Engineer with a rapidly increasing range of industry experience looking to bring strong instincts and a proven record of procedural compliance, process management and strong operational skills to an enterprise environment.

Current Certifications

Linux: LPI

Microsoft: MCP, MCSA, MCSE

Cisco: CCNA, CCNP Certified since 2001 and renewed every 3 years (current)

Experience

Senior Network and Systems Security Engineer

September 2002 - Present

Marketing Software Company is a Los Angeles based integrated database marketing services firm focused on creating profitable and sustainable growth for its clients, which include some major retail companies in the US. I am responsible for:

- Designing, securing and monitoring network devices and production servers across 3 datacenters to ensure business continuity for our environment and our client's database applications. Configuring routers, switches, firewalls, load balancers and servers to meet our environment's needs.
- Ensuring that compliance and contractual requirements are met. Complete monthly and quarterly tasks to ensure compliance with SSAE 16 guidelines. Review and complete security questionnaires for our annual SSAE 16 audit as well as for prospective clients. Review and process security requests insuring compliance with established guidelines. Review proposed access control lists and implement them. Review and implement requests for IPSEC VPN remote access connectivity for Customers and Partners.
- Monitoring our environment using various tools including: Nagios, Cacti, Alienvault as well as Cisco's IPS and IDS modules. Responding to any incident detected following established procedures and guidelines.
- Conducting quarterly penetration testing on our entire network using Tenable's Nessus and Qualys SAAS. Applying any remediation required upon discovery of any vulnerability or unpatched system.
- Troubleshooting at every layer, from the wire to the application in a complex environment

Network and Systems Security VP

April 2004 – January 2010

Raideil Inc. Hosting company

Deploying, Implementing and Administering systems and network for Raideil Inc. a web hosting company. Built and designed the hosting environment on a Linux Redhat platform.

Deployed Email servers using Qmail, Spamassassin, Clamd. Web Servers Apache, Tomcat and IIS. DNS implementation. Network Security and monitoring.

Partner and Technology implementer

February 2001 – September 2007

Dvarchive.com, Los Angeles California

Part of the core team that conceptualized, envisioned, planned and managed www.dvarchive, from the 'drawing board' to the launch. Dvarchive is one of the first sites of its kind to offer royalty-free downloadable digital video clips in both NTSC and PAL formats. Responsible for all team selection, project management, technical and business research, technical preparation, all media implementation, international marketing, site growth and maintenance, technical flow and image delivery.

Technical Operations Manager

February 1999 – September 2002

Wish You Were Here Stock Footage Library, Burbank California

Management of all technical aspect of the stock footage library including network administration, new technology implementation, and all troubleshooting.

Technical lead on all new projects and new websites. Balanced between technical and video elements of the library as needed. Reformed library system (of 72,000 images) to a searchable online B2C user-friendly, industry standard, viewable database, where a large amount of new sales leads now come from the website.

Photography Lab Supervisor

September 1994 – September 1997

Lebanese American University, Beirut Lebanon.

Cameraman, Editor

September 1995 – September 1998

Ministry of Social Affairs, Beirut Lebanon.

Education

International Consortium of Technology Professionals 2000 – 2002

Anaheim, California: Network Maters Program. Intensive two year program specialized in enterprise networking technology designed to develop senior level hands on skill-sets by working with enterprise-level networking equipment. Obtained all my technology Certifications.

Lebanese American University

1991 - 1994

Beirut, Lebanon: B.S Liberal Arts (Radio TV Film) External Degree with the University of the State of New York.

Additional Skills

Programing experience: Python, Ruby on rails, Javascript, JQuery, PHP, Objective C, Swift.

Languages (fluent): English, French and Arabic.

Reference Available Upon Request.